<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Survival Analysis on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/tags/survival-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Survival Analysis on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/survival-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parametric Regression Model in Survival Analysis</title>
      <link>/tspost/parametric-regression-model-in-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/parametric-regression-model-in-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}There are differences between Parametric Models, Semi-Parametric Models, and Non-Parametric Momdels.  The graph below gives the main pieces of information. A survival analysis can be defined as consisting of two parts: the core survial object with a time indicator plus the corresponding event status (used to calculate the baseline hazard). The second part of the survival model consists of the covariates.  We have to keep in mind that both of these parts can have a different distributions, or it is totally possible that no distribution at all is assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Analysis: Kaplan-Meier &amp; Logrank test</title>
      <link>/tspost/introduction-of-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/introduction-of-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}The ultimate goal of survival analysis is to gain information on the expected duration of time untill one or even more events happen. Survival analysis is applied in different fields and most of these fields have different terms for the same concept. So, sometimes it is called Reliability Theory or Reliability Analysis in engineering. It is also called Duration Analysis in economics or Event-history Analysis is sociology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>