<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TSPosts on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/tspost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TSPosts on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tspost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Product Demand</title>
      <link>/tspost/forecasting-product-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/forecasting-product-demand/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Accurately predicting demand for products allows a company to stay ahead of the market.  We will predict demand for multiple products across a region of a state in the US. Then we will roll up these predictions across many different regions of the same state to form a complete hierarchical forecasting system.  We need to forecast the future values of our data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Time Series and Forecasting </title>
      <link>/tspost/applied-time-series-and-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/applied-time-series-and-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this particular field R is favored over Python. In fact, R has more features for Time Series.  A precious resource is the Rob Hyndman’s Blog. It explains step by step the standard univariate time series analysis.
FIRST  TRENDING DATA  In this example we explore how many people are working in a country: unemployment rate vs. labor force participation rate. That is used for propaganda purposes, because low unemployment rates show an optimistic picture about the economics of a country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Nets and Interactive Graphs</title>
      <link>/tspost/neural-nets-and-interactive-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/neural-nets-and-interactive-graphs/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this post, we use some fairly new technology of time series analysis namely neural nets and interactive charting tools. These techniques are the state of the art. The dataset we use for this example has: missing data, outliers, poor formatting.  The dataset i about restaurant at a campsite that is open whole year. There is a peak season in summer, and so we aspect to have seasonal data and trend might be present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply Chain Foundations</title>
      <link>/tspost/supply-chain-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/supply-chain-foundations/</guid>
      <description>body { text-align: justify}  INTRODUCTION  Who do companies care about supply chain management? We know that food is always at the grocery store, and clothing at the department store. How they get there and who is making those items are there every single day? This is the job of supply chain manager. 
In supply chain management we start with purchasing, some people call it Procurement. The second part is Manufacturing and Operation, where the product is made, and we have to do that quickly and being able to do on a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Background for Time Series</title>
      <link>/tspost/statistica-background-for-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/statistica-background-for-time-series/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this post we will review the statistical background for time series analysis and forecasting.  We start about how to compare different time seris models against each other.
Forecast Accuracy  It determine how much difference thare is between the actual value and the forecast for the value. The simplest way to m ake a comparison is via scale dependent error because all the models need to be on the same scale using the Mean Absolute Error - MAE and the Root Mean Squared Error - RMSE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>