<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Neural Network learn? An example of risk of churn of custmers of a bank.</title>
      <link>/aipost/how-neural-network-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aipost/how-neural-network-learn/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Having a one layer neural network (single layer feedforeward) with the output value to be compare to the actual value. Baed on the activation function we have our output. In order to be able to lear, we have to compare the output value with the actual value via the cost funtion which is the half of the squred difference output and actual value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer segmentation via K-Means &amp; Hierarchical clustering</title>
      <link>/mlpost/customer-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mlpost/customer-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Consider to have a big mall in a specific city that contains information of its clients that subcribed to a membership card. The last feature is Spending Score that is a score that the mall computed for each of their clients based on several criteria including for example their income and the number of times per week they show up in the mall and of course, the amount of dollars they spent in a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the sucess of a new product via multiple classifiers</title>
      <link>/mlpost/estimate-the-sucess-of-a-new-product-with-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mlpost/estimate-the-sucess-of-a-new-product-with-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}These are a series of analysis to illustate the main classification algorithms and their advantages. The table shows the business clients of a company that has just launched a new product online. Some of the clients responded positively to the ads by buying the product and other responded negatively by not buying the product. The last column of the table tells for each user if the user bought the product or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrea Perlato</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>body { text-align: justify}  I started my caree as a Data Scientist more than 10 years ago in the field of Neuroscience at the University of Verona - School of Medicine, Italy. As point person in data analysis, I studied the single and multi-unit recordings from behaving non human primates. Moreover, I have been conducting psychophysic experiments on human subjects to investigate the brain plasticity in drug addicts. Find out more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>