<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Survival Analysis on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/categories/survival-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Survival Analysis on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/survival-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cox Proportional Hazards Model</title>
      <link>/tspost/cox-proportional-hazards-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/cox-proportional-hazards-model/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}An hazard rate is the probability estimate of the time it takes for an event to take place. The event can be anything ranging from death of an organism or failure of a machine or any other time to event setting.  There are external factors that influence the probabililty of an event, covariates. For example: how many miles was the car used or did the owner exchange the oil regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parametric Regression Model in Survival Analysis</title>
      <link>/tspost/parametric-regression-model-in-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/parametric-regression-model-in-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}There are differences between Parametric Models (e.g. Kaplan-Meier), Semi-Parametric Models (e.g. Cox Proportional Hazard), and Non-Parametric Models.  The graph below gives the main pieces of information. A survival analysis can be defined as consisting of two parts: the core survial object with a time indicator plus the corresponding event status (used to calculate the baseline hazard). The second part of the survival model consists of the covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survival Trees</title>
      <link>/tspost/survival-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/survival-trees/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}A survival tree is a decision tree fitted on the survival data. It allows covariates to be incorporated quite like in a Cox Proportional Hazard.  When we use a survival treee, we have to keep a few things in mind. First of all, it is a very good choice for huge dataset. Decision or survival trees require a huge amount of data to get precise enough.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>