<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Series Analysis on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/tags/time-series-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Series Analysis on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/time-series-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Classification</title>
      <link>/tspost/time-series-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/time-series-classification/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In order to perform a Time series Classification we use Decision Tree, and then we look at the performance of the classification. 
We use the Synthetic Control Chart Time Series. This dataset contains 600 examples of control charts synthetically generated by the process in Alcock and Manolopoulos (1999).
data &amp;lt;- read.table(&amp;quot;C:/07 - R Website/dataset/TS/synthetic_control.txt&amp;quot;, header = FALSE)# Data Preparationpattern100 &amp;lt;- c(rep(&amp;#39;Normal&amp;#39;, 100),rep(&amp;#39;Cyclic&amp;#39;, 100),rep(&amp;#39;Increasing trend&amp;#39;, 100),rep(&amp;#39;Decreasing trend&amp;#39;, 100),rep(&amp;#39;Upward shift&amp;#39;, 100),rep(&amp;#39;Downward shift&amp;#39;, 100))# Create data framenewdata &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Clustering</title>
      <link>/tspost/time-series-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/time-series-clustering/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Clustering is the task of grouping s set of objects in such a way that objects in the same group are more similar to each other than to those in other groups. Connectivity-based clustering connects objects to form clusters based on their distance. A cluster can be descibed by the maximum distance needed to connect parts of the cluster. At different distances, different clusters will form, which can be represented using dendrogram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Background for Time Series</title>
      <link>/tspost/statistica-background-for-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tspost/statistica-background-for-time-series/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this post we will review the statistical background for time series analysis and forecasting.  We start about how to compare different time seris models against each other.
Forecast Accuracy  It determine how much difference thare is between the actual value and the forecast for the value. The simplest way to m ake a comparison is via scale dependent error because all the models need to be on the same scale using the Mean Absolute Error - MAE and the Root Mean Squared Error - RMSE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>