<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/categories/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Descent Step by Step</title>
      <link>/theorypost/gradient-descent-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/gradient-descent-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}INTRODUCTION  In statistics, Machine Learning and other Data Science fields, we optimize a lot of stuff. For example in linear regresion, we optimize the Intercept and Slope, or when we use Logistic Regression we optimize the squiggle. Moreover, in t-SNE we optimize clusters. The interesting thing is that gradient descent can optimize all these things and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science using Agile Methodology</title>
      <link>/theorypost/data-science-using-agile-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/data-science-using-agile-methodology/</guid>
      <description>body { text-align: justify}  INTRODUCTION  A data science team asks great questions, explores the data, and delivers key insights.  The best way to generate business value is to deliver a constant stream of key insights in short two-week sprints.  A short sprint will also help the team pivot so they can ask new questions based on what they learn from the data. 
WORK ON A DATA SCIENCE PROJECT  Typical project upfront requirements and we need to understand what we are going to build before to start the planning project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Processing</title>
      <link>/theorypost/event-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/event-processing/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Process Data  Event data consists of three basic components: the why, the what and the who.  Analysing event data is an iteractive process of three steps: extraction (from raw data to event log), processing (removing redundant details, enrich data by calculating variables) and analysis.  The analysis could be for instance which are the roles of different doctors and nurses organization and how they work together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Probability</title>
      <link>/theorypost/continuous-probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/continuous-probability/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Empirical Cumulative Distribution Function  When summarizing a list of numeric values such as heights, it’s not useful to construct a distribution that assigns a proportion to each possible outcome. It is much more practical to define a function that operates on intervals rather than single values. The standard way of doing this is using the cumulative distribution function (CDF).  As an example, we define the empirical cumulative distribution function (eCDF) for heights for male adult students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many Monte Carlo are enough?</title>
      <link>/theorypost/how-many-monte-carlo-are-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/how-many-monte-carlo-are-enough/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Here an example of the The birthday problem solution via Monte Carlo. Suppose you’re in a classroom with 22 people. If we assume this is a randomly selected group, what is the chance that at least two people have the same birthday? 
This is a problem of discrete probability. 
All right, first, note that birthdays can be represented as numbers between 1 and 365.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monty Hall Problem</title>
      <link>/theorypost/the-monty-hall-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/the-monty-hall-problem/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In the 1970s, there was a game show called Let’s Make a Deal. Monty Hall was the hos, this is where the name of the problem comes from. At some point in the game, contestants were asked to pick one of three doors. Behind one door, there was a prize. The other two had a goat behind them. And this basically meant that you lost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>